I will draft an edict to depose the Crown Prince
朕は詔を起草して太子を廃するつもりである
To satisfy them
彼らを満足させる
All dismissed for now
みんな先に帰ろう
Let me have some peace
私を少し静かにさせてください
Yes
はい
Ruolan
ルーラン
Fan Zhong
ファンチュン
Have Marquis of Yongning guard the empress's tomb
永寧侯に皇后の墓を守らせる
Your Majesty
陛下
Your servant Xie Xuan requests an audience
僕謝玄拝謁を願います
In the future, Great Xuan will be restored
来日の大きな宣告が戻ってくる
Lost territories will be recovered
失われた土地が戻る
In the history books
歴史書で
Not only brother-in-law
義兄だけではない
Not only sister
姉だけではない
There will also be a record of me, Xie Xuan
必ず私謝玄の一筆もあるでしょう
Fan Zhong
ファンチュン
Bring me a jug of wine
酒を一杯持ってきてください
The 21st year of Longwu
隆武二十一年
Xie Xuan was executed by Emperor Sikong Yao
謝玄は宣帝司空耀に捕えられた
On charges of persecuting loyal officials
忠良を迫害する罪として
In the capital
彼は首都で処刑された
At the same time
同時に
The emperor also ordered
宣帝はさらに命令を下した
The Crown Prince
皇太子を任命する
To be confined to the palace
宮中での出入り禁止
Time is up
時が来た
Execute
処刑
Brother-in-law
義兄
Speaking of defeat before the battle
戦う前にもう負けを言う
Staying in the capital has made your bones soft
あなたは北京に長く滞在しすぎて骨まで柔らかくなった
Since we must fight to the death
死ぬ覚悟で戦う
I won't be such a coward
そんな悪党になる資格はない
Brother-in-law
義兄
I request to lead the cavalry out of the city
私は八百の精鋭騎兵を率いて城を出るよう命じた
You, as a Xuan person
あなたは宣伝者として
Acting as a dog under the enemy's tent
敵のもとで犬のように従う
Xie Xuan, deputy general of Yiyang garrison
弋陽守軍副将謝玄
One day
一日
Give me one more day
もう一日ください
I will personally lead the battle
私は自ら前線に立って戦いを監督した
Under my command
私の部下
There are also over a hundred men
100人以上もいます
To clear the way for Your Highness
殿下のために道を開く
General Zu
祖将軍
Please rise quickly
早く起きてください
You've worked hard, General Zu
お疲れさまです祖将軍
I will reward you heavily
私はあなたを重々しく賞します
Read
念
General of Agile Cavalry Zu Yue
骠騎将軍祖月
Loyalty and courage bestowed by heaven
忠勇天授
Meritorious achievements are clear
勲功が顕著である
Rescued the emperor and quelled rebellion
勤王と乱の鎮圧
Merits surpass all officials
功績を群臣に冠する
Now
今
Specially promoted to Grand General
特進大将軍
Envoy with credentials, bearer of yellow battle-axe
節を持ち仮の黄鉞を使う
Commander of all military affairs
中外の諸軍事を統率する都督
Granted the nine bestowments and special honors
錫は九つの特別な礼で特別に与えられる
May enter court without hurrying
朝貢に急がない
Addressed without name
名を崇拝しない
May enter court with sword and shoes
剣を履いて殿に上る
Opened a government office equal to the Three Excellencies
開府儀同三司
Your servant Zu Yue
臣ソゲツ
Kowtows in gratitude for the imperial grace
感謝の意を表する